Are you Jason?
He's talking.
>> I have to switch to my truck. I'm sorry. I gotta disconnect here. Let's see if this works. Can you hear me?
Yes. Morning.
How are you? Good morning.
>> Let me get your paperwork up here. I'm gonna call the meeting to order
at 09:00.
Let me get the agenda.
Okay.
I'm taking minutes as well as
>> everything else, so bear with me. Yep. I'm the the volume on my phone for some reason isn't very loud, so I'm gonna kind of have to put it to my ear to hear you a little bit. I apologize.
>> Okay.
Maybe, I don't know if I can
open my,
I don't think I can increase mine.
We're gonna do the pledge of allegiance first,
here's the flag.
Indivisible,
with liberty and justice for all.
>> Okay.
There is nobody on for public speak, I guess. Where is my pen?
I just have it.
No,
>> I don't have to get a pen. Hold on. Here it is.
So, Jason, the first thing I have to do
is
give you the oath
because you didn't fill out the form,
which has Okay. On the bottom.
Okay. I will
let me turn this up.
Do you hereby
declare under penalty a false statement that the above statement according to the best of your knowledge
and remembrance and belief is a true statement?
Yes,
ma'am. Okay.
>> So now we need to go
and start with you've got all these vehicles that you sent me pictures of are unregistered?
That's correct. Yes.
Is there a reason why they're unregistered?
They're they're not roadworthy vehicles
any longer.
>> Is there any reason why you still keep them? I mean, can you I'm working on that this year, cleaning this out.
>> One of the trailers belongs to a friend of mine who was supposed to store it here for a month, and that's been a few years now. So
I'm actually
and then I had another person that was renting in the house next door from me, and he passed away in a motorcycle accident, and now his life belongings are in there, that of which
I had to go through the due process because the state had a right to those for a period of time.
So I have to get rid of that now
and
that'll get the black trailer and the black tractor out of here. I'm going to have to give him a timeline essentially because
obviously we're well past the thirty days, which we discussed initially.
One of the trailers I use for storage, it's become it was in rough shape when I bought it. I bought it because the roof was collapsed.
I repaired the roof for storage and
it's since started leaking again, so as consequence the floor is rotted now.
It's not really being utilized efficiently. It's more or less
there's very little in there that I would use any longer. So
I'm gonna be getting rid of that as well. So the black trailer and the black
truck
are not even yours?
>> They are not mine. That's correct. Yep. And which one
I mean, are there is that the Great Dane
>> trailer and truck? Yeah. I have two Great Dane trailers here. One I own, which is the white one,
and the black one belongs to the owner of the black Volvo truck.
>> So
in in your
you know, you laid out the things that you had for me in your email, but I don't know one from another, so help me out here.
>> Yeah, the Volvo,
the 1998,
I believe there, it's a '98 trailer and '98 tractor, if I'm not mistaken.
Those aren't mine, but they are here,
That of which the assessor's office insists that I'm responsible to pay taxes on.
Yeah, I guess if they're on your property.
>> That's-
that's the deal.
As of last year,
I had also
two vehicles from the individual that passed away.
I got rid of one of those last year.
I also had
it wasn't an unregistered vehicle, it's personal property tax which we can address later I suppose.
But I got rid of one one pickup truck.
Another vehicle that I had just not renewed the registration because it was something I didn't use anymore.
I
I got rid of that.
So
I I also work full time obviously and I have three young children.
Mhmm.
My time is limited to
I've been I've been this has been a work in progress for many years as a matter of fact. So
I've also cleaned out from the previous owners on this property over the last ten years. Now none of these vehicles are registered then?
That is correct. Okay. They don't have valid registrations at this point. The registrations have expired essentially.
You have title?
>> On
the 1993
Great Dane,
I don't have a title. Essentially, I have Bill of Sale per se,
that of which I wouldn't need a title to get rid of it anyway because of the age of it. Right.
I'm confident there's a title for the black
Great Dane trailer and
the great and the Volvo tractor. Those are titled.
I don't possess that title, but they are titled.
And there's a 2,003
Ford Explorer out here
that I
purchased with the great idea that I was going to
bring it out in the woods and make go over jumps with it. And I purchased it for $300 and it still sits
without doing so at this point.
So.
>> Ford Explorer. Okay. That's I see that one. Yeah. Yep.
That's 1993,
did you say?
>> 2003.
That is a 02/2003.
Okay. Yep.
There's a the Ford Econoline,
which is like a '19
I think that's a 1986 I have it listed as. I don't have that right in front of me.
1985 Ford Declanoline.
>> Yeah, that is something that I that was a truck I had many years ago. They got used in business and
has a bad motor. It's been sitting for,
I don't know, twenty something years, but
it keeps some things dry in the back of the box, which is still good. So I just kind of use it as a shelter storage more or less. Is that the pickup truck?
>> No. It's the red box truck, Georgia. Oh, big Okay, the one with three trucking on it.
The Ford Econoline.
Yeah.
You can tell I don't know the vehicles, right?
You know what a Jeep is.
Yeah, I do. Oh, okay.
>> So, the Great Dane 48
trailer,
that's the gray one, right? Yep.
Okay.
Now, I had no way of
going into the NADA book, which is where they value things like this because Right.
Down office is closed on Thursday at 04:00,
>> and I didn't get these till 06:30 something. I I apologize for that. I have a very hectic schedule. I got hurt last week, which didn't my schedule is no less.
Okay.
>> Yeah. I understand things happen, you know. Yeah. But so we're gonna have to rely on
let's see. They're assessing those vehicles at 20,136?
>> That's correct. So in my rough numbers,
they're giving me an actual value of close to $30,000
when the reality is
if I were to sell everything here, I would probably see about
maybe 4,000,
$5,000.
Mhmm.
>> And that's possibly being generous to the fact that that tractor and trailer could be purchased by somebody that would want to make it roadworthy.
Right. I'm looking at That tractor's been sitting for about seven or eight years.
It sat at a different location years before it got here.
The driver of that had
couple of run ins with the law involving alcohol, and he no longer is able to drive at all regardless of any vehicle for that matter.
Yeah. That of what she gives me is a reason that he can't get here to get it out. However,
we're at a point where there's there's gonna be an immediate timeline. I might at some point, I have a potential buyer for this property,
so
I'm starting to clean it up and we'll see how that goes.
>> Have you inquired with anyone like
Andover Auto Parts there on Route 6, whether or not Well, they
>> know that, I
can't locate the title for that 2,003
Ford Explorer,
although I did have it in my possession at one point. I can't locate the title for that, so that
if I either have to go back to the owner I got it from that was the original owner, apply for a title, or I have to wait till 2023
so I can scrap it. That
Mitsubishi
pickup truck
that belonged
to the son of the individual that was renting from me that's deceased,
I can scrap that. The problem is I have
tenants that left trash in the back of there, so I need to find time to clean that out so I can call somebody to come and get that,
which is in fact going to happen this spring at some point.
>> That's a Mitsubishi,
okay.
I'm trying to find that oh here it is okay.
That's a 1987.
Yes.
>> You know Georgia can I make a comment? I mean I think cutting to the chase if we were to do a minimum value of 500
for each of these pieces.
It would put us six
times
five right?
Thousand.
Yep.
>> I mean,
we
don't have them in front of us. We can't examine them closely, but based on the pictures
and information he's presenting,
I think the $500
value on each one is more appropriate,
but I'm certainly willing to listen to
you people as well. Linda, I do you have
>> would be fine with the $500
for each, which is the minimum.
2,003.
>> I'm happy. I'm happy here on FaceTime. I I have you FaceTimed on my phone. I, excuse me,
there I came to the shop just in case you want to see anything. I can I can tour you through that the best I can if you choose so?
>> Okay, I'm just The one that looks the best is your Explorer, but what issues does it have?
>> I'll give you a quick tour of that one. It's a real
gem with 240,000
miles, I believe. I'll
give a look at this real quick just so you can understand.
The paint looks good.
>> From the road, if you take a good picture in the right light, it does. Yes.
So I'll show you.
I'm just gonna give you I'm gonna turn this around so I could show you the body here.
This is the rear bumper.
This is the rot, the body damage. Could you open that door?
I know you're not here to smell it, but if you know what mice smell like Oh, yeah. You can see actually
the mouse over here ate part of the leather seat it appears.
There's evidence of mice
pretty thoroughly throughout this vehicle. Yeah, I'm good with 500.
Okay,
>> if you want to make a motion. I make a motion Georgette that we value each of his presented
automotive pieces
at $500
a piece.
I will second that motion.
>> Okay, let me write this down.
One
second
Linda.
Okay.
And
since I have no clue.
All in favor.
Aye. Aye.
>> I'm going to abstain because I'm totally out of my element here.
Alan, yes,
it passes just the same.
One abstention.
Okay.
All right.
Now we have to go on to your
Personal property for business? Yeah.
Need to know what do you have
for
equipment. What's the business?
>> So
for many years we did excavation and concrete
and
what we've
evolved into at this point is we're doing new foundations for the crumbling foundation epidemic in the Northern
Eastern section of the state.
So basically,
we do new foundations now and that's about it.
I do have some residual excavation equipment,
but basically
the basis of my business is
I bounce from one job to the next with a trailer full of planks to form up footings. We form up the footings, we pour those, we disassemble that, and then we move on to the walls.
Okay, what do So we
I have concrete
panel selection
or
collection
over the last year.
I'm
estimating the original value of all the concrete panels at about $14,000
total
of initial investment, and that's been a lot of that's panels that have been used for the last, I bought them used, they've been used for the last
fifteen years.
As long as you maintain them, they're fine to keep using.
Is that right? Is that I have a registered vehicle that's our primary tool for that because we put all our concrete panels in steel cages
and the vehicle I bought for that is a it's a crane truck essentially.
And then we lower the cages into the hole. We take our forms. We assemble them.
We disassemble them, put them back in the cages after we've poured concrete,
lift them back out with the truck,
and
put them on the truck, drive it to the next job, and do the same thing over and over. So we're doing that. This year, we're probably going to do that about 38 or 40 times.
We're
>> hoping to get 40 foundations in. So essentially, that's what we've evolved to. As consequence,
I have a little bit of equipment.
I'll go over this list with you, what I have left.
Previous years, I don't know if you have the previous year's list, I had a loader, that of which I got rid of. I had a backhoe, that of which I got rid of.
I can as well, I'm at my shop now, so I can show you this equipment as demonstration as well, per video here.
Over here I have my 1996,
I believe it is. It's a Hitachi EX 100 twenty-three excavator.
I'm going to show it to you here.
This was a primary machine for me for many years. At this point, it has ten thousand hours. It still has some value
even with the ten thousand hours on it. We use it once in a great while, but because we don't really do excavation anymore, it doesn't get used much. However, I would value that at roughly $8,000
if I were to sell it in the open market.
I also have 2003
Mustang.
Mustang is the brand, 2054
is the model.
It's a Mustang 2054
skid steer
that I bought new in 2003
for,
I believe it was $26,000
with accessories.
>> Can I stop you Let for a
me stop you for a minute, Jason? Sure. Yep.
We don't we don't do anything with registered motor vehicles.
Well, wouldn't be registered.
>> That's correct. This is a this is a skid steer.
It's a what? A skid steer. Skid steer. Show I'll show you the picture. Yeah, like a like a bobcat, but it's a different brand. I don't know if this Right. If you could see that with the sun.
So that would be something.
>> Okay.
This is None of none of those are listed in in what I Well,
>> that's probably because Roberta made a guess,
but she didn't actually know and now the gentleman's explaining to us. Okay. What he has. So, last year I had a detailed list for them.
>> I don't know if you've acquired that. I tried to look for it in my files. I wasn't able to locate it.
So I just kind of started new from what I have left. I've gotten rid of quite a bit of anything I'm not using really,
with the exception of these two pieces of equipment that I think I'm going to keep just so I can have them around for a little bit of this and that.
I've essentially gotten rid of. I had sanders here, those are gone.
I had some miscellaneous plowing equipment, that's gone, with the exception of one plow that
belongs to one of my registered trucks.
So
I have this Mustang,
which has an unknown amount of hours
as the hour meter stopped working at fourteen hundred hours, which was about
nine or ten years ago, I would say. What do you call that thing? A skid steer? Skid steer. It's like if you ever hear a lot of people refer to it as a bobcat. Yeah, I know what a bobcat looks like. I'm just trying to write down these things. Yeah, So What do value that at?
I'm going to value this at $4,500
because it does run.
Right now, it is not inoperable,
but I have parts here to repair it. We essentially
use it around the yard to move around concrete panels and things of that nature at this point. Now what are the concrete panels worth do you think?
My initial investment is roughly $14,000
for the concrete panels that I have.
But they're old.
>> It
was $14,000
most likely of a cumulative value over the course of time.
I'm estimating what I paid for my initial set, know, was probably 10,000 or $11,000 at one point, and this year I added a few thousand worth of panels. I
bought a partial set that was used.
At a certain point in the panel's life,
they really have no value. They're a burden value per se because
once the face of a concrete panel isn't any good anymore, you can't really use it. Or if the structure of the panel, because it has to hold the weight of concrete when it's wet. Okay. Until the concrete sets.
You ever be able Essentially we have to sell have
I'm sorry? Would you be able to sell them?
>> And
if so, for a
couple dollars a piece basically,
you know.
How many,
what does that amount to total roughly?
>> If I were to sell every panel I had? Yeah. I might get 9 or 10,000 for the entire set at this point. You're trying to put a value on.
Yeah, I would
say if I sold my entire set, I might get 9 or $10,000 at this point. Okay. Now let me explain something to you.
>> When you go and you
fill out the personal property declaration,
these
things,
they would decrease in value automatically
from these forms.
Yes.
So it would benefit you to do this every year and not have to pay penalties.
>> Yes.
Last year I did it. Oh, did? Have intentions of doing it this year with
my work schedule. I'll explain something to you that it's very difficult to get employees
for a concrete business for a number of reasons. One of those being with this epidemic,
a lot of people can do much better for themselves
collecting unemployment if they're already doing so. Well, true.
So as
an example, for the spring, I have two employees with me that just came back to work.
It appears as though one of them might be leaving me for a
mandatory
state issued vacation
of one to two years.
I've had an add out for
the last six or eight weeks,
and in six or eight weeks I've had four responses
and nobody's a tradesman in this field because if they're laid off, they can probably,
with added
unemployment,
they can get about a thousand dollars a week, 900 and something a week, whereas
a full week for me, even with a good rate of pay, they might take home $809,100
after taxes.
And that's for an experienced concrete person
that's a tradesman per se. So
with that in mind,
I don't know what my point was with that, but
>> Well, the reason why you didn't go in and fill out the forms. Oh yeah, I'm sorry. Yes, so
>> essentially, at the end of the day, I'm responsible for the agenda for the people that I work for. I work for
one contractor exclusively, more or less. I do a little bit of other concrete work as well for my own, for other contractors or people or whatever.
But
my my hours are are beyond
what my body is able to handle at this age, honestly, and
I'm working on that. However, it's just
my schedule doesn't stop. I have five crews that come in behind me. We have crew that comes up from Pennsylvania,
so we have a scheduled date on the calendar
as to when they're coming back up to put houses down and lift more up.
So
we we really have to be diligent to
making sure we stay on track even if the weather changes a little bit. Okay.
>> So now what about equipment in your house? Do you have a computer, a printer?
>> Oh, I have a laptop
that I do all my invoicing.
I paid probably $400 for that, dollars $3.50.
And how old is that?
>> Maybe
five or six or seven or eight years old. Probably five or six, I would think.
Had it for a while.
Alright.
What about a printer?
>> I have a printer.
That might have been a $100 or $60 or something like that.
>> Okay. So we have
see those are part of the things you need to declare.
>> Yep, I also
saw what
I would,
as opposed to going through a 100 pieces of hand tools and office equipment and things of that nature,
What I did is I basically put a rough bulk value of
hand tools, so things like this that would be in the toolbox in my truck,
a machine in my shop that we use to finish the concrete floor, tools that we would use to fix equipment or trucks.
I put a rough value of $5,000
bolting all that together, which I think is pretty reasonable.
I can show you some of this equipment.
Hand tools and machine.
>> -So
this right here is a floor finishing machine.
I bought that one about
five years ago and I paid $800
for that five years ago. That compactor,
I paid
700 or $800 for it. That was a number of, that was probably ten years ago.
We do maintenance to them, we still use them here and there.
But I put a bulk value
of $5,000
on all that stuff more or less.
Okay. Including the mechanic tools?
>> Yeah.
I mean,
those are tools that I bought when I was working as a mechanic when I was 18 years old.
Obviously, depreciate over time.
>> Now the values you're giving us now are what you value them at this time.
>> That's correct. Okay.
I'm trying to write down and keep track so we can be fair about it. My collection of mechanics tools over the years has become much, much less extensive.
You can see them kind of piled on top of my toolbox. I got wrenches on the walls. Yep. We use
the tools to repair stuff, but we're not tooled up as an adequate repair facility would be either. Correct. Under any circumstance. Do
you have like
a desk and a chair and
>> I have a very old desk right here
in the office.
Okay.
>> This is world headquarters right here. This is where all the corporate activity takes place.
>> And the office party?
I'm sorry? In the office party?
>> This is where the Christmas office party is right here. Yeah. All the all the CEOs and CFOs meet here for the Christmas party.
We take the mouse traps out of the corners away at that point. Okay.
You use a phone for business. Correct? I use my cell phone, the one I'm talking to you on. I don't have a landline at all anymore.
All, everything in this office, including that old computer there about six or seven years ago,
unfortunate to still have this building because
the building or the pole or a tree right next to it got hit by lightning and
everything melted.
The phones got destroyed, my router got destroyed.
So at that point,
fazed. I didn't get new phones. Just,
>> I I didn't really use the landlines anyway. So But if you use your cell phone for business, that's figured into it. So
Okay. I'm saying desk chair and phone, we need a value on that that you would put.
>> That desk I probably paid $200 for it. I know for a fact that chair was
a treasure find I called them, it was on the side of the road, somebody else had had enough of it and I thought it was perfectly adequate.
Okay. So that lives here now.
>> Jason, when you had last done your personal listing,
what was the value then?
>> Want to say it was probably
20 something thousand at that point,
that of which I've alleviated quite a bit of that equipment.
I had sanders.
I also had more unregistered vehicles which aren't applicable obviously at this point because they're not here. All right, well really quickly on what we've gone over, the concrete panels at 10 ks,
>> the Hitachi at eight, skid steer at 45,
laptop printer 500,
hand tools five ks, cement finisher eight,
computer eight,
that's
computer printer.
I marked that down to like 300.
The computer printer was what?
300.
>> Well,
you can buy a good printer for about $60 at BJ's any day of the week, which is probably what computer that one
>> and the printer. Oh yeah, I'm sorry. I'm reading my notes here. Compactor, the floor compactor was eight So,
>> so I had bulked the floor compactor, the floor machine, the hand tools,
tools that would go with me in my pickup. I bulked that all at $5,000
roughly.
I mean, you know, I probably have
300 items, so it'd be kind of ridiculous to value a worn out hammer that I carry in my pickup truck. The paperwork's not worth it. We're just going to put kind of a bulk value per se, you know what I mean? So the concrete panels 10 ks, the Hitachi eight,
>> the skid stair 45,
and then 5,000
for the miscellaneous
tools.
Correct.
That comes up to like
28 or 29,000.
>> Okay, we're gonna have to categorize
these separately according to the form,
okay? So
what I'm gonna do is read to you the furniture, fixtures, and equipment,
and we need to put a value on that. That's number 16 in here.
Uh-huh.
>> And so if you wanna take the desk, the chair, the phone,
that kind of thing, that's just the office furniture, not the equipment, Georgette? No, the office furniture fixtures,
like the phone, the chair, the desk,
those are
What about the computer? No, that's
>> category number 20. Electronic data processing,
and that's a computer and printer. We have to do these separately so that
Roberta can adjust them according to these categories.
Okay.
So we need to break it down. And then they have,
let's see, expense supplies. The average is the total expended on supplies,
which I don't know whether you don't keep any supplies in your
garage or whatever, right? Not really, no. Okay, so number 23 is zero.
We have
other goods including
leasehold improvements.
I don't know what that means, but you have farm machines and mechanics tools.
Farm machinery.
I think mechanics tools is
Wrenches,
screwdrivers,
all that stuff. Correct.
>> Yeah.
I'm trying to
She's got a category of farm tools, but I think mechanic tools is closer. So a number 19.
>> Well, if we were gonna separate like the concrete floor finishing machine and the compactor
and then the mechanics tools,
you know, I'd say the
compactor and the floor machine are worth 1,500. The mechanics tools are worth 3,500 or something like that, you know. So we could put that under mechanics tools,
1,500?
>> I would say that like the tools that I, if you wanted to put the
compact or in the floor machine and the mechanics tools together, we would say 5,000. If it's going to be a separate category, I would value those at 1,500 and put
the mechanics tools together.
>> 5,000. We'll put them together. 5,000.
Yeah. Okay. Okay. Okay. So that's category number 19.
And
then the furniture, fixtures, and, you know, the desk, the chair, the phone,
roughly just some
>> kind of value on that. A few $100 maybe. You know, I mean A couple 100?
>> Yeah. Okay. And
then number 20 is electronic data processing. That's the printer
and the laptop.
>> Yes. Put that at a few 100 and maybe my phone is incorporated in that. The phone is incorporated in the in the furniture fixtures and equipment. Okay. Yeah. Okay? Yep.
>> So we'll make that 300 and it will make the laptop and the printer 200.
Yep. Okay. Okay.
>> Now 23 is zero because you don't have any of that.
I don't know like an excavator.
>> Yeah basically he said the skid steer and the Hitachi
together
is 12,500.
>> Okay so that I think would have to go under other goods.
I don't see any other category for that.
>> With rental. Well then you got to include the concrete panels with it. So it's 12.5 plus 10.
So it's $22.05.
>> $22.05.
Okay.
And we've got
I'm gonna have to say 24 I don't know category
24 other goods I don't see any other category.
What does she have 23?
>> Okay.
You don't have anything for 23. Alright. And Jason, you don't keep anything in inventory,
right, that you buy consistently?
>> Not really. Like, you know, we buy we buy material like when we do a foundation,
we have rebar. We get rebar dropped off at the job. We put it in the wall. We have anchor bolts dropped off at the job. We put that in the wall. We put our panels together.
We pour it. We use it. We don't count that.
>> Yeah, I mean, that's supplies essentially, you know? Right, yeah, I'm just asking for inventory, if you have an inventory.
>> No, no. Our primary
commodity is concrete,
you know, so we just call it concrete company. They bring that out in trucks obviously already mixed,
know, we just essentially,
excuse me, essentially we're
selling labor is what we're doing, you know what I mean? Right.
Knowledge.
Assessor's
office uses
>> a category of farm tools
and that's where a good bulk is.
I wonder
like the the loader, the backhoe, the excavator, could those be considered farm tools?
>> I wouldn't call that farm tool. Oh yeah, I don't I don't really think there's anything categorized here as a farm tool because we're not doing any farming
>> per se. You see, have farm machinery too. Yeah, but you couldn't use a skid steer on a farm.
>> Well, you could use a skid steer on a farm, but it's not what we do with it. It's essentially a construction equipment. Yeah, you can It's what it manure in the the couch stalls or something like that. Yeah, yeah.
>> Yeah, they don't really have any category for construction
thing here so I don't know what to do with it. 24
other goods.
I'm
just going by what she's using and she's using
that's Roberta as I'm talking about.
She did use farm tools.
That's
like
$6,200
on here.
>> Yeah, but it's more than that even for Justice Gitz there.
>> Oh, I know. So she was just making a guess. She doesn't know about all these.
>> I think,
I think the, what was my, what was my proposed
value for this year for personal property
for the business?
Do you have that in front of you? On here,
>> you had 20,136
for
unregistered motor vehicles and 32,560
your Yeah.
>> Yeah. So that was that's going
what I know is it went up a certain percentage from last year.
Yeah. And I went in the office and filed all that and we discussed things like the backhoe
and the loader were pieces of equipment that belonged to my father that were kind of too old to use really on a job.
She said well because it's here and you run your business here, you have to pay on it. So we
included those. Since you know, had aspirations of restoring them and using them around my house because they were my father's. Sure.
And I've, I've, I've
separated myself from this at this point and I'm okay with that. I got minimal amounts of money,
but it is what it is. I just,
the reality is me having time to restore those. Right. Isn't a reality at this point in my life, and if they sit for another ten years,
I might not even be able to get them in a shop somewhere to restore them. So
>> Right. Okay. That's that. Just let me review
the 22,500.
Those were
the excavator,
the skid steer.
Now what else?
Concrete panels.
>> Concrete panels.
Okay. Yeah. So we got 9,000.
I put 9,000 concrete
panels.
I think you said 10,000, didn't you, Alan?
10,000 for the concrete panels. No, I wrote 9,000 because of the value, I guess.
>> Yeah, 9 or 10 or whatever. Mean,
suggest- suggestively, it's all depreciable,
but I
understand it has some value, you know. I just- I know with them saying I'm at 32,000 of my appraisal,
or my appraised value, that leaves me at 40,000 of realistic
value, which is
not the case, you know, so. Okay.
>> So with 9,000,
8,000 and 4,500,
that comes up to 21,005
for the I guess it's number 24
would be
I don't know. I'll let her categorize it. I'll just,
you know, put down what it is.
So I guess have we got everything here? $21.05,
$50,045,000
>> for what is this? Mechanics tools? Mechanics tools. Yep. Mhmm.
>> And
laptop
and printer,
300,
and phone no. Desk and phone oh, 200.
And the desk and phone is 300.
55,
that's 6.
265.
Anybody else add these up?
>> I made a rough guess when we started at 30 ks.
So $26.05
is in the ballpark.
>> Yep.
Okay.
Alright.
I hope I can
decipher my notes
here. EDP supplies. You don't keep any supplies. Okay. See, the penalty alone is 25%.
So you really don't want to.
We can't do anything about the penalty. That'll be adjusted automatically by that. Yeah. Yeah. I understand that. Yeah. Okay.
Linda, you're making a motion?
Hold on.
I'm getting 20.
I'm getting 27.
>> So I'm not sure what I'm doing wrong or. Well, you can make it twenty six five or '27.
We're we're still there, you know? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Just have to
>> so that would make it 22
for the
machinery and stuff.
Mustang's good.
Okay are we doing 22 even for the machinery?
>> Yeah I just have to adjust
98 is 17.
All right 505,000
for that. Okay so I've got 9,000 for the cages and panels
8,000 for the excavator
and 5,000 for the skid
steer
and that comes to 22.
22.
So with 22.
>> Plus 5,000
for the tools
is 27 and then another
200 plus 300, right? 500, yeah that'll make it 5 That's
27,527
thousand 500. I'm adding it up as we go.
I got that I'll make
a motion for 20.
What did I say? 27.5?
Yes ma'am.
275.
I'll second that motion. Okay,
all in favor?
Aye.
>> Aye.
Okay.
It is passed. Yes. So we've got 3,000 for the
unregistered motor vehicles and 27,500
for the business
things. Okay.
>> Very good. Jason, you're all set. Okay. Well, I'd like to extend my appreciation for everybody's time because I know this is something
you do for the town and
I'd like to say that I do appreciate that as well. So. No problem. Thank you. Okay. Thank you. Y'all have y'all have a great weekend. We will. You too. Take care. You'll
be getting a letter from me, Jason.
Okay, very good. Thank you.
>> Okay, next on the agenda, we don't have Brian Maudsley,
so we'll have
Dennis Foran.
Okay, Dennis, are you here?
Yes.
Okay.
No video.
Video.
Hey, look at that.
Okay.
Modern miracle.
That was magic.
>> All right. Now,
what is it?
What is it that your appeal is about you?
Excuse You? Me George.
For what year?
>> George I just want to before we get started
Joan is with me also here
and
yeah she's reminding me also that I should
solemnly
swear
that the evidence
I should give concerning this case shall be the truth the whole truth and nothing but the truth upon penalty of perjury.
Well, did You sign
signed it on the form.
Right. Okay.
Well, anyway,
>> that's just I'd like to take the oath too. You
like to Okay, swear clear on your penalty of false statement that the above statement according to the best of your knowledge, remembrance and belief is a true statement?
So help me God.
Okay. It's not on there, so I'm just reading it. Yes. Okay.
So,
that's
I went through the stuff you sent me last night. It was quite a bit of stuff.
I'm not sure was
it 2018
that you no longer had registration on it? That's correct.
Now did you pay?
I paid the taxes in 2018.
But that was for
the bail and Well
>> I actually
it
was assessed originally
2,000 well
for for the $2,017
>> list, I guess. Right. That's what you paid in 2018.
Yeah. I paid that
for it. Now they
failed the
emissions test
in late
twenty seventeen.
I know I saw that. Right.
Okay.
>> I
think to clarify this is really simple.
What we're asking for and this consultation
with the assistant to assess the Roberta.
As an unregistered vehicle.
We are appealing.
Twenty
eighteen twenty nineteen and 2020.
Okay.
Because we were assessed at for those years.
I do have the figures. Yeah we have the amounts. So the gross assessment
>> for
2,000
yeah let's see this would be 2018.
Well that would be the you know off $20.17
grand list. Right. Was 3,190.
Is that for two vehicles or one? That was for just one That was for 2001
Jeep. So the the tax the main part of the tax bill
did
you know consolidated
both vehicles but it also shows the split between the other. Right yeah I saw that. Okay, I did see that. Yeah. And then we received a bill recently
>> for the Jeep was assessed at $3,350
Now,
For 2020
Yeah.
And we have we did not receive another bill until that.
So
>> Well,
did
going just going back to 2018
where what happened was that
it had failed the
emissions test right at the end of twenty seventeen to get it re registered
and the registration
due date was in March
2018.
And
so right at that right after it failed and I was going to try to just get it through again
the
brakes system failed,
the rear brake system,
brake lines and everything else and I got a quote to fix it
and just the brake lines alone were
about 600
or so and then it really needed to replace the wheel cylinders and the master
cylinder.
It was a dual brake system so I could still drive it on the front brakes
but
I couldn't really bring it in that condition back through emissions again without getting the work done.
So at that point I was looking at a value of over
$1,000
to get all that brake
system repair work done
and the value of the car or the vehicle
because earlier in 2017
I was looking at swapping
for other maybe another Jeep a little bit newer than that one.
And
I valued that Jeep at that time as true value on the market given its condition and mileage at that point it had over
230,000
miles, 232,000.
Right.
>> A ton of mileage, yeah. Yeah, so it's a lot high mileage and there's a lot of deterioration in the body and everything else.
It was worth about $1,000
at that point on the market and I was looking even at picking up another one for about 1,500 with
a lot less mileage and a
fair amount better condition.
So that's about how I pegged the actual market value of it.
And then
lo and behold the
brakes failed right when I was trying to get it re registered and retested.
Right.
And
so I
kind of put it aside to figure out what to do because I really didn't want to,
at that point,
and I did have some
fair amount of past experience in doing brake work.
Excuse me. I
guess I'm not
audible.
Did the audio go?
No.
>> We can hear you. Oh, we can hear you. We're all listening.
Wasn't sure if Georgette Georgette was speaking,
I couldn't hear Georgette. Georgette, your audio is gone.
>> Oh no, not again.
Yeah, again.
We had this problem last time.
Zoom is really frustrating.
Commend you guys for Yes.
>> Yeah.
Absolutely.
Especially for going through all this one meeting after another.
Mostly I second it.
But anyway,
going back to the issue with the vehicle.
Yeah, that
I wanted to try to do it myself.
>> I can't. She can't hear you. Just keep she's not Okay. Do you want She has to call in or she's gonna have to call in on a phone.
>> Do you want us to stop until she gets back on?
>> Well,
Linda, can you call her and tell her to use the phone?
>> I don't think I have her phone number.
You should have gotten that last time because we had this problem last time. I have her phone number. I just have to go upstairs.
>> All right, you find a phone number please, Mrs. Foreign? Yes, thank you.
Mr. Grimaldi, can you hear us?
>> Nope. Yes, I can. Oh, good.
Sorry, it took me a minute to unmute my mic. No, that's all right. That's all right. So
>> we're waiting for Georgette to
rejoin us and then we're going to get to you. I we have,
I think you'll be glad you waited for the last time. Really? Well, that's that's encouraging.
>> So what's going on? The speakers aren't working or something? Well, Torchette has problems.
>> Some we're not really sure why with her audio.
One minute she's on and one minute she's off.
>> She's talking and she doesn't realize we can't hear her. Oh, how about we do something like this? No, she just
left the meeting, didn't she?
She's
>> gone now. Yeah, think she's trying to sign in again. I was just telling her to phone in.
>> I have a number.
She's she's gone so she must have left.
But go ahead, give me your number.
looks like 80085.
All right, let me go try to call her. That was the last number I hope I hope it's correct.
>> All right, I went out and back in again. Can you hear me now? Yes, we can hear you now.
She is.
Keep this process up before anything else goes wrong.
>> We should speed it up. Yeah I'll try to speed this up.
Were you able to
hear each other?
Yes. It
was just me. Yes.
>> Wonderful. So was there any conclusion?
Well, just
to say that
>> that I was just giving the reasons
why I had
set the car aside, the vehicle aside. I just couldn't No, I heard all that. I couldn't get back to it to do the repairs myself and time just went on.
And so
the end of twenty
eighteen,
I had kept the engine going in the yard. The registration
had expired during 2018
so I no longer drove it and
I did try to at least keep the engine going and
move it around a little bit but then it
over the winter of twenty eighteen, twenty nineteen that the engine
kind of just set it aside a little too long and it
was no longer operable
and at that point
that was the last time I ever had started it or driven it.
So it's in your driveway?
It's sold it. We
>> sold it for junk
because
just
this past October,
I was trying to bring it to a head and find and make a decision myself if I was gonna
try to get back and repair it and restore it, but it really and
I had tried to start it up for an individual
in mid, well it was right in June
and
I wasn't able to do it. I could have got about maybe 4 or $500 for it
at that point
and if I could have gotten the engine going, but I wasn't able to do it. The engine
sputtered and then it
had a little mini catastrophe
under the hood there
with the bell.
So what is the value of the vehicle? The value of the vehicle I would peg it at
maybe for that first year when it was the engine was still running,
say $520.18?
That would have been $20.18.
>> Yes. Now you realize the minimum that we can value that at
is 500 in this town?
Well No, I disagree. It
is 500. Ask the assessor.
Here's what the actual value That's the minimum. I
realize that.
I
>> contradict you. The other thing too is I just like to say, and I did talk to Roberta about this.
The assessor
is an employee of the town of Andover.
The border assessment
appeals
is an elected
town agency,
you are totally independent
from the assessors office.
Now I do value
his information,
and you should listen to him. The statutes which govern
the assessor
are totally different than the statutes
that govern the Board of Assessment Appeals.
And we sent you that in your pocket.
>> I see it. But Joan, if you'll let me explain. We went to classes
about this.
And the guy teaching the class said that the assessor of each town sets the minimum value
of unregistered
motor vehicles,
or
actually motor vehicles, period.
And so
we have a 1947
Jeep that hasn't been registered or doesn't run for thirty years. I still have to value it at
$500
because that's the least they will accept.
>> Okay. May I answer
that?
Sure.
Okay.
I too have gone to training
given by
the Association
of Assessing Officers.
And I've had
different conversations.
So, I would say to you
that anyone who has
anecdotal
information
regarding
any of their vehicles,
that they also could appeal to the Board of Assessment of Appeals.
But what I'm also telling you is the statute
is very clear.
The delineation
given to the Board of Assessment Appeals
by statute
and the statutes
given the responsibility to assessors
is different.
So why we come to the Board of assessment appeals
is to assess
the value given by the assessors office.
And then, if you're stating differently.
Show me the statutes,
quote the statutes,
quote the charter
quote town ordinances.
Well,
>> also,
I would I was just gonna add myself that the
I understand
for 2000 after 2018,
in 2018
I guess I would it would still be considered as a motor vehicle whereas after that it's personal property.
So I don't know if that makes Yeah. But anyway,
the other thing is the
after 2018
to for in other words for 2019
and 2020
value was only $125
because I have the receipt for that and I have the transaction information.
So that's 2019?
That's 2019
and 2020.
125.
>> Right, the engine was not running during 2019
it was not running in 2020.
So that's what they call scrap value.
Scrap value, junk value.
>> And
having a receipt.
That means that receipt
is fair market value.
And that is also getting very clearly
in the
handbook for the B.
Baa.
>> So you're saying the Board of Assessment appeal does not have the authority to contradict you.
No,
>> I'm saying the board of system appeal to discuss
all the evidence and make the determination,
which is your
duty and responsibility.
I just present the evidence,
and then you decide,
I would never presume to tell you any amount.
I'm just presenting evidence,
And then also So Georgette,
>> if I can ask you, we had this discussion at the last meeting and it happened to involve Mr. Grimaldi's land.
And the question came back,
do we have the authority
on changing
what you are telling us is minimum value?
And you
talked about the land, right? That's a different You talk about the cars. That doesn't apply here.
No, no, no.
>> You're at the same training that I was at. Did the guy not say that the assessor sets the minimum value of?
>> I didn't understand that it was set in stone for us. I didn't understand that.
And so last meeting,
I said to you,
you're telling me,
is that the law?
>> And you said, I'll go back and ask him. Yeah, but I don't wanna discuss that now. I want to stick with the motor vehicle. We're going to deal with that after Well, I thought you were asking them both questions.
That's two different categories.
I know, but you were supposed to go back and ask them. When it comes to real estate, it's different than it is for motor vehicle or personal property. I
>> I didn't know that you're listening to me, Georgette. I said, when we had that meeting,
you indicated,
Linda,
correct me. You indicated that you would go back to the assessor and ask, not just land,
but vehicle.
>> No, I didn't. I don't remember the part about the vehicle. Okay.
All right. I just don't remember it. I'm not saying it didn't happen, but I don't remember it is recorded. So we can go back and listen. Right. Can I just make
>> one statement
or
because
I did review the statutes myself too?
And
I don't think this is the Well, after 2018,
as I said before,
in 2018,
it was taxed as a motor vehicle. But in
2019 and 2020,
it was another category is personal property.
Correct. You have land,
you have motor vehicles,
which come pretty much through the
Connecticut
Motor Vehicle Department.
And then you have personal property when it's totally on, you know, or something's not registered
and it's no longer
from the motor vehicle department. So for personal property,
I saw no statute that said where you have to go to
any kind of
a minimum value other than say antique
automobiles you can't assess for more than 500.
That's the only thing that I found that referred to $500
was for So
>> can we go and do 500
for $20.18
and 125
for 2019
and 2020?
Exactly.
That's what I would suggest.
>> Yep, exactly. I'll agree to that. We're in total agreement. But one of my concerns is
Linda and Alan, did you get the materials that we sent to you by email?
Yes.
>> Okay, good. All right. Because I think I'm really
settled. I'm really sincerely that everyone should have all materials before the meeting and have all their questions answered in regard to procedure before the meeting. Thank you very much. We got a deal unsettled.
>> We're settled and happy. Thank you. And thank you very much and thank you. Well, we gotta make a motion and I'll pass
>> make that motion.
500 for 2018,
125 for 2019
and 125 for 2020.
I'll second that motion.
>> All in favor. Aye. Aye.
I'm going to abstain. Thank you.
>> Okay,
motion passed.
Thank you very much and thank you all for your service. Thank you. Thank you. Welcome.
>> Bye. Bye. Bye.
20185201912520192125
okay
Linda motion.
Allen.
Second.
Yes.
Obscene.
Okay.
On to the next one.
Now,
mister Grimaldi.
This is
oh, this belongs to the other guy.
Okay.
Now
the
>> that what the what the assessor told me about the
0.92
acres building lot,
The
value is set
during reval.
And they're uniform for all the properties.
This is in the lake area.
In that particular, not
waterfront,
but in the lake area,
it's 0.92
for a building lot. And it's assessed at 82 or appraised at 82.5.
And it's uniform
for all of those pieces of property.
I don't feel comfortable changing one.
Why?
Because
it's not treating everybody uniformly.
I disagree.
>> And when the new we're getting a reval this
year. So when they come out next year, it'll be a different value as of the October 1 grand list.
>> And here's my position.
I say that everybody in the town of Andover with a building lot
got an evaluation
just like this gentleman's.
As you point out,
the Lake area, Lake District,
if you own a building lot in the Lake District, not waterfront,
they got a bill.
Mr. Grimaldi is the only individual
disputing the bill
as his
right.
Nobody else cares to or
wishes to, and they haven't done so.
But we have an obligation
as the BAA to
look at the information presented,
the information we have
and make a decision.
And you
Georgette told us Linda and I, and again correct me Linda,
that you talked to the assessor
and
the understanding is
he set that value
but it's not an obligation
by law that that's the value.
>> That's correct. That's what I understood. What he said was,
>> you can do anything you want. Right.
But he said, just remember
that
when you start treating
certain people differently than you start treating other people, you're opening yourself up for an awful lot of
appeals.
>> So
we're not treating him any differently. Mr. Grimaldi got a bill.
Joe Smith down the road gets a bill.
Mr. Grimaldi says, I don't agree with this and I have reasons
not to agree with this.
And he presented it.
Well, he didn't really. He just said, I don't agree with it. He didn't. No, no, no. He cited other lots in the area that have been on the market
for considerably
less.
And
they haven't sold.
>> They're not selling. But we don't see the proof of that. So what I did
>> is I called someone at Keller Williams who lives in Columbia
and sells the Andover properties.
And he said from their record information,
the average
building lot
non waterfront is
48.7
for a building lot. That's what it's actually selling for.
>> And what is the In Andover? That's in Andover. In Andover.
Is the history?
>> Some of the results are,
for instance,
Bunker Hill Road,
which is on the market for twenty five days is eight acres,
60,000.
That's not the lake area. Okay,
>> it's not the lake area, but he doesn't have
any diff whether you're in the lake area or not, he's in the forest. Nobody sees the water.
They're a mile away from the water.
You may call it the lake area, but it's not exceptional.
>> Do you know where this property is? Off of Merritt Valley.
Mr. Gormaldi's
Yes.
>> Mr. Gormaldi, can you hear No. Yes. I am. No. No. You're, you're mistaken. I am
On Lake Across the street from the lake, probably,
I don't know. It's on Lake Part of a mile from the lake, across the street on Lake Road.
So what are you closest to?
I'm sorry. What do you mean? What road?
>> Yeah. Where in terms of where you are, where this property is, what's its closest road?
>> Probably Erdoni.
Erdoni Road? If I take a left out of my dry out of the driveway, we we come to Erdoni Road. That would be the Probably the closest. You can see his his house
>> when you go around the curve on Lake Road, and the property is part of it's in that same area is it not?
>> Yes it is. The property is next door. It's it's next door to where I live right now. So you can't compare something on
Bunker Hill or wherever.
>> It's not the same. Well, Brian DeMoore's family sold 11 acres
in the area of this gentleman's property
and he got 160
for 11 acres.
>> Well, do you, I mean, if you had his sheet, you would see that he has 17
acres.
Right. I have And all they value it is at $23.09.
>> But you're saying that the building lot
he has one building lot cut out of that property. Is that correct?
Yeah.
>> That one building lot cut out of that property is valued at
83?
82.5.
>> And the same thing with the lot that his house is on, that same
measurement
and
the area and all that is 82.5
because
that's what they do with the 0.92 building.
But all the others, I mean, he has 17 acres. It's valued at 23.9.
The other one where his house is, I think that's yeah
is 3.15
acres valued at 4,400.
So you're not
>> Okay, so let's visit another question. There was a
previous member of our board
who did take the town to New Britain Superior Court and won
>> her case. Actually, Alan, don't say that. It settled
out of court because he put your land in forestry for next year. But for that particular year, you didn't file to put it in forestry.
>> So let's I'm not talking about my land.
A former
board
member
Which, Okay. Female
>> Okay. Whose name I'm not using. Okay. Who has a house on the lake.
Okay. And testimony
recorded testimony
in court
by a town
secondary appraisal
put lakefront
value at 100,000
per
acre.
Lakefront.
And
so
what I'm saying is by testimony of town
people that while he was hired by the town to be a second opinion
because the assessor was being challenged, they had to get a second opinion.
And that independent appraisal person
in testimony to Superior Court
said that per acre value
of building lots is 100,000 lakefront.
>> I'm
not sure what your point is. We're not talking on a thousand. We're talking So we're saying his land is not lakefront
and it's point how much Straight from the lake.
>> It's across Lake Road from the lake. Right. So if you're saying the higher value property is lakefront and it's a 100,000 per acre
and he's out of that area.
And and how many square feet how large are your lot is it?
Mister Gribaldi, how large a lot is it? Which lot are we talking about? The one the building lot.
>> The building lot is seven seventeen acres.
That's the entire building lot? We see No, no. Well, we seem to be talking about two different things here. Right.
When I appealed, I appealed the
point nine two acre building a lot that you're claiming is uniform
throughout the town. That's what I'm claiming. That's what I'm appealing. I'm sorry. Okay. The unit price, I'm looking at
>> what they call the card from the assessor's office. The unit price is $67,000
and then they
adjust for different things. There's different codes of adjustment.
And then it ends up to be 82.5
for the land value.
The 17
acres is only 106,000.
>> I am not appealing to 17 acres. I'm not Oh, I know. 17 acres. I'm talking about
same thing I talked about last week, was it? Two weeks ago. Point nine two. Point nine
two acres that is So, being valued the
these, there could be a brand new house right on the lake
and they're going to value that building a lot 0.92 acres at 825.
>> Could be a house not on the lake, not waterfront.
No.
>> That's a two I'm point
sorry. You just said that
every
lot in the lake area is valued at $82,005 The I also said not Not
>> waterfront. Okay? Not waterfront.
I mean, they all start somewhere. And then there's adjustments according to whether you waterfront,
whether you're lake view, whether you're lake area, wherever you are, they have adjustments.
It's done by some program
that does that.
Okay. So you're telling me two different things now.
Yes, No. I'm
>> you are. You told me last time I was here that every lot, the base value $82.05
for that 0.92 building lot throughout town.
No, I did not.
It's The Lake District.
>> I said Lake area,
but not right, Lake District, but not waterfront. Waterfront is much higher.
Okay.
>> Yes, that's what I have. And I have it in your email. So that is definitely what you said. Okay.
>> Now my information from the realtor was that the average
assessment per acre for a building on was $48.07
for the entire town.
No, that's not true.
That's totally untrue.
>> Well, no, that's true for Keller Williams.
That's what they gave me. That's the average for the entire town?
Lake Andover? The average for the town of the Andover building lots is $48.07.
That's from Keller Williams realtors.
That's an opinion.
>> And what does Mr. Grimaldi think that his
lot?
What would be more appropriate?
>> Mr. Gramaldi, what do you think your lot is worth? The 0.92? Exactly
>> what I put on the appeal application
that I sent back to you guys.
So
75,000.
It hasn't changed.
Sorry, I couldn't find It's
>> on the appeal.
It says reason for appeal assessment of building lot excessive
estimated value of the property being appealed 75,000.
I don't have a problem with that personally.
>> I, you know, you seem to be really hung up on where the property is located in town. I have a lot right down the road from me. I could throw a rock at it.
It's
been listed for 69.9.
a little under two acres, 1.96
acres.
69.9,
this is an approved building lot across the street from the lake.
Actually has a better view of the lake. On what street?
Lake Road. Down the road from me on Lake Road. Lake Road. Yeah, for 69.9,
it's been on the market for one hundred and seventy one days.
I have others here, but they're not on Lake Road.
You know, same thing I quoted last when I was here last.
So,
to go back to my original appeal, I am appealing the
$82.05
value of that point nine two acre building lot. If I can buy a whole lot
with acreage
for less than $70,000,
how can you be valuing my building lot at
$82.05?
That's my appeal. That's my reasoning.
And there are several I have a whole pile of them here,
which, you know,
you want to dispute a realtor who's in the business that does this every day and what lots are selling at, well, go right ahead, but these are all listed
online.
Anybody can find them.
That's what they're selling for or not selling for, I should say. But you're not appealing what they're valued at. You're not appealing the value of the same thing that your house is on.
No, I didn't appeal that. I'm talking about the new bill, new bill because I just got the new bill
on the brand new lot
and I'm appealing eighty two five.
>> And you think it's 75 and I think that's reasonable.
>> I have current assessment for the grand list of twenty twenty,
seventy four five.
That's what the
real estate assessment notice from the town of Andover says
that the current assessment for the 2020 grand list is $74.05
>> So, I I don't know. I have no idea what you're talking about. I have the card right here. Okay.
This was sent to me by the assistant
assessor.
>> This was sent on 02/28/2021
for 353
Lake Road and
it has the map and the block
I don't know if 353
>> Lake Road is the house I live in now
That's not what I'm talking about.
Well, both of these pieces say 353
Lake Road.
>> You look at the very top of the card I'm looking at, property location 357
Lake Road. If you look at the other one, the very top where it says property location, it says 353 Lake Road. I'm talking about 357
>> Lake 0, see 357
Lake Road, right, but the owner, I was looking at the owner's address, sorry.
This is
353.
This the property location is 357
Lake Road.
It has the MAC, the block, and the lot.
And this is from the assessor's office dated twoeighttwenty
twenty one.
It talks about current assessment. Last year's assessment for 2019
was zero because you hadn't evidently broken it out and decided to sell it. And it says current assessment for $20.20 grand list,
gross assessment 74.5.
So I'm confused.
I'm sorry. What are you confused with?
You want us to increase it by 50?
>> I'm not appealing the assessment, I'm appealing the land value.
Okay, the land value,
which is I'm assuming this means the appraised value is $82.05
not the assessment
and
you would like the land value to be 75,000
yeah the appraised value
>> For the value of the land. The appraised value $82.05.
And you want it to be For 70
the point nine two acres, yes. Correct.
>> Believe that that is I will make a motion
that the point nine two acres
that Mr. Grimaldi made a building lot
be appraised at $75,000
I will second that motion.
>> Okay.
All in favor? Aye. Nay.
That was two to one.
It's approved.
>> Okay. I would just like to know why
you would vote nay. I mean, thank you very much. I appreciate No. It's because
It doesn't make sense to me.
>> It seems to me if you thought the land was
appraised too high, you would have come
for your own as well that's appraised
at the same thing, same value.
And I believe
unless there's a particular reason that your lot
deserves to be less than what
other people in the same area would be,
just to say I don't think it's worth that much to me is not proof.
Like if you have a house and you say, oh, it's appraised too high, show me
other ones at the same type of house or whatever that are valued less.
The thing is to treat people equally and be fair.
And that so I don't believe
that this is fair to take yours
one of yours down and not other people's and not your other one.
>> That's all. That comment right there, I agree with you 100%.
You should not be just taking mine down. This whole town should be looked at. John should be looking at every every
building lot in this every home in this town
because he's assessed that point nine two acres excessively high. The proof that I have shown you is there's lots for sale all around here
for less than $70,000
That's the proof.
This is supposed to be this, this, I'm sorry, keep saying assessment. Maybe that's why I'm,
maybe that I'm misspeaking here. I'm talking about the value of the land.
Okay? If the value of the land, according to John, is $82,500
I should not be able to buy lots around here for less than $70,000
Buildable. I'm talking about approved building lots now, not just vacant land.
I have a pile of approved building lots here for under $70,000
I think one of them is $74,000
The one down the road is $69.09
dollars All right, that's what I'm saying. I'm saying that the value
of lots that I can buy right now that aren't even selling, really, which
I can buy now is less than what John is saying the land is worth,
The value of the land.
That's that's just my that was my whole argument. The whole, you know. And we are going through a reevaluation
right now. So, we'll have to see what it is for next year. Okay but I understand the real estate market is like booming right now so my thing is john's going to jump on that and this brand is going to go up because if it does then I'm going to be right back here oh boy
and everybody else will be
>> If the value of these properties around here go up equally, then I have nothing to talk about, okay, but they're not,
and I mean I'm just talking about close to this area.
I went you know, Coventry, Hebron, all the area towns,
proved building lots selling, not selling for less than what he's valuing them at is just not fair to everybody in town.
And I agree, you shouldn't just be lowering mine. I'm happened to be the guy that came and appealed it. Right, we could only look at people that appealed it. Right, I understand, but I think somebody should be talking to John and saying, listen, this isn't fair to everybody that lives in this town, that you're valuing this 0.92 acre lot more than it's worth. You do understand that
>> if they lower all the values,
they still need to appropriate the same amount of tax money to keep this town running.
Mill rate The goes
>> rate is going to go up and you're going pay the same taxes you pay now.
>> I understand that. Okay? But we can get into the mismanagement of this town at a different meeting.
>> Know? Listen, we can get into mismanagement of the state and the country, but we're not here for that. I agree a 100%.
>> Mr. Grimaldi, thank you for coming back to us and letting us have time to explore the issue. All right, I know, I don't wanna hold you much longer. I'm sure everybody wants to get out of here.
What has gone on, okay, is that for what, fifteen years now, I've been paying a lot of taxes to the town, and quite frankly, I don't get much in return. Be grateful you're not on the water, I am.
Oh, no, I understand. I think those homes are way overvalued.
Well I'm
>> surprised you're not appealing, but that's
another thing. Okay? So anyway, so how do I do I get some kind of notice or something? I
>> write up the minutes
Oh, Okay. What happened,
and I send them to the assessor's office in Reverham.
I also write a letter to each individual
explaining
what we decided,
which you already know. But
that makes it official. And I have to get that all done
by the end of this week. Actually, it has to be done by the end of the month, which I just make sure I get it within the same week. So you should be getting that. Okay. Now I'm up to my eyeballs in my church stuff because we're starting our first takeout dinner today.
Oh no kidding. So if you like Polish food come over to St. Peter's in Hebron.
The pierogis? I'll go for that. Oh, we have. It's kielbasa and sauerkraut. It's all the sauerkraut is homemade. It's pierogis.
It's stuffed cabbage.
It's sweet and sour cabbage,
rye bread,
sour cream for the pierogies,
and
dessert.
That's today? Church down here?
>> No, St. Peter's in Hebron on Route 85. Okay.
Okay. Yeah. And it's $14 You don't even get out of your car. You just pull up and you tell us how many meals you want, you pay your money, and off you go with your food in your car.
Well, I hope you I'll be taking the money.
All
>> All right. Right. I just want to thank everybody and Mr. Roy I want to thank you for being an advocate, know, understanding my situation. Thanks for coming. Just have a second opinion then Alan, that's all. No, understand. I just needed to understand. Okay.
But thank you very much. I appreciate it. All right. Thank you. Have good day. Bye.
>> Okay.
So those are the three cases.
I guess we're pretty much done. I'll have to write it all up while I still have it fresh in my memory. Well, I make a motion to Okay. Close your
Okay, I make a motion that we oh, you made the motion already, right? I'll need a second. I'll second. And it is 10:30.
ADJ
10:30.
Take care, John.
Alright,
thank you. Bye.